MUSIC: Mambo No 5 by Lou Bega
# A little bit of Erica by my side
# A little bit of Rita's all I need... #
'Can I take your order?'
Hurry up.
Burger. Extra cheese. no onions.
HORN BLARES
Burger. Cheese. Onion.
'Window number two. please.'
Muffed it.
You forgot the milkshake.
- Banana...
- Banana milkshake.
What?
Banana milkshake.
Burger virgin.
I can do this.
Look. you'll have to go back round again.
How many points. do you think. in a glass of wine?
- Five.
- Three.
Nicoise salad. Pizza Express.
Bit of tuna. bit of egg. few beans.
bit of olive?
19 points.
19?
All in the dressing.
You need a break.
You should take a holiday.
I was thinking of a week in Ibiza.
I hate holidays.
Bit of sun.
bit of karaoke.
I don't sing.
All Swedish people sing.
- Abba.
- RIVER SCOFFS
- Roxette.
- RIVER LAUGHS
A-ha.
A-ha? They're Norwegian.
I don't know how you eat this stuff.
A couple more times and your stomach gets used to it.
- RADIO:
- If you're in the area. if you're not going to the game.
let's continue with a request from Josie in Lewisham.
Here's Tina Charles with a classic disco anthem.
MUSIC: I Love To Love by Tina Charles
# Oh. I love to love... #
Sing. you nutter.
# But my baby just loves to dance... #
Sing!
# He loves to dance
# He's got to dance
# Oh. I love to love SHE LAUGHS
# But my baby just loves to dance
# Oh. I love to love
# But there's no time for our romance
# No. no. no
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# The minute the band begins to swing it
# He's on his feet to dig it
# And dance the night away
# Stop
# I'm spinning like a top
# We'll dance until we drop
# But if I had my way
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# He wants to dance
# He loves to dance
# He's got to dance
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# But he won't give our love a chance
# No. no. no
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# The minute the band begins to swing it
# He's on his feet to dig it
# And dance the night away...
# Stop
# I'm spinning like a top
# We'll dance until we drop... #
Same car.
Yes.
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# He wants to dance
# He loves to dance
# He's got to dance
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance... #
Now. take it slowly.
LAUGHTER AND CHATTER
MUFFLED CHATTER
HORN BLARES
Yo!
What's going on?
RIVER BREATHES HEAVILY
- Out the way!
- What you doing. man?
Riley!
KNOCK ON DOOR Police!
KNOCKING CONTINUES
Police!
Urgent assistance required at the Tracey Estate
by DS Stevenson and DI River.
In pursuit of a male...
Open up! Police!
Wait!
HE SCREAMS
GLASS SMASHES
CAR ALARM BLARES. DOGS BARK
Nice.
WOMAN SCREAMS
Light blue 2001 Ford Mondeo.
You've got no plates. no visual ID...
- It's the same car.
- It's the third you've called in this week.
He jumped.
That's because he grows weed.
Christopher Riley has two convictions for dealing.
a third and that would have been him away for years.
The press are going to be all over this.
We won't name you but somebody will.
What were you thinking? You're not on the case!
It's the same car.
Well. we'll leave that to forensics. shall we?
You see psychs in the morning. like I asked you.
Rosa. 9am. Be early.
She'll only say what everyone else says.
You can't bring Stevie back.
What does she know?
HE LAUGHS Exactly.
Exactly!
Right. what does she know?
What do any of them know?
I identified the car as that seen on the night of Stevie's...
Would you like to amend that sentence. Inspector?
I identified the car as that
POSSIBLY seen on the night of Stev...
Of Detective Sergeant
Jackie Stevenson's murder...
..and I pursued the vehicle.
Why didn't you call for backup?
We did.
"We"?
Who are you talking about?
He's not even on the investigation.
He spots a beaten-up car then.
based on reckless instinct.
chases a random man to his death.
Or we're looking at our first viable lead.
It's not beyond the realms of possibility. Riley has got form.
But if Riley did kill her.
I'd have preferred to have questioned him.
He should be on compassionate leave.
He won't take it.
It's not as if I haven't tried.
Try harder.
He has an 80% clear-up rate.
Then give him a good reference.
I'm encouraging him to focus back on the Erin Fielding case.
We do have a duty to him.
To ensure that if he's not mentally fit to work then...
Yes. I will call it.
I want to see River's psych report as soon as it's in.
Oi.
The last holiday you took.
you called me with heat stroke...
..from Scotland.
I told you. I hate holidays.
So. get back to work then.
We made a promise to Erin's mother.
Morning.
Do you know your teeth are the last thing to rot?
After bones and hair. and skin.
George Washington wore hippopotamus teeth.
You've run out of Shreddies again.
So. are you going to get my suitcase down?
I've got masses to pack.
I know you've been looking at my Facebook page again.
'This train is for Bank.
'the next stop is West Bay.
'On leaving the train...'
There are 12 questions
and 12 boxes to tick.
I make an assessment
based on these questions and the answers you tick.
It's procedure.
OK.
I'm going to read them out
and you simply answer yes or no.
Have you experienced or been exposed to a traumatic event?
During the traumatic event...
I don't know what I'm doing here.
You witnessed the murder of your colleague
less than three weeks ago. River.
When an officer has witnessed a violent death.
it's protocol to offer psychiatric counselling.
There are concerns...
..about how you're handling her death.
- CHRISSIE:
- So. let's interrogate the things we do know.
It is a blue Mondeo.
but is it the same car?
Was it Riley driving that car the night Stevie died?
If so. motive. Why did he kill her?
We've checked those closest to her.
so now we want to focus in on Riley.
Anything...
ANYTHING you can find that might link him.
This is Stevie we're talking about.
OK.
Rosa.
That's a good name for a psychiatrist.
I thought it went quite well.
There's stuff you could have said.
How long we've worked together. when we met.
how I bug the shit out of you.
how I won't give you any rest...
Just stuff... Stuff.
What are her credentials? References?
Where does she come from anyway?
She done nine years with the Met and six years in Broadmoor.
River. Detective Sergeant King.
Ira.
From the Hebrew.
meaning "watchful"
or "full-grown".
Father - Muslim. mother - Jewish.
I'm the original Gaza strip.
If you could bring him up to speed with the Erin Fielding case.
Her mother called again.
Boyfriend confessed two and a half months ago.
Aten Olama. 20 years old.
Awaiting trial.
He won't tell us where the body is.
- Any previous?
- No.
Her mother wants to bury her.
She sends us reminders of Erin most weeks.
I'll talk to Aten again today.
Take Ira with you. It would be good to get it off the pile.
Is that my baby-sitter?
How did it go with Rosa?
Oh. good. Yeah. very good.
We made very good progress.
You were in there less than ten minutes.
She asks too many questions.
We're trying to link that car to Stevie's murder.
otherwise you chased an innocent man to his death.
He jumped.
His girlfriend is expecting a baby.
She's already gone to the press.
Hold it together.
We're all struggling here...
but I'll take you over a roomful of those goons.
Prove me right. yeah?
- The DAC is on his way up.
- He...
Sod off.
Good book?
It's interesting. very interesting.
I haven't finished it yet.
'The extraordinary tale of Dr Thomas Cream
'has long haunted detectives past and present.
'To many. I was the Lambeth Poisoner.
'To the few. I was their angel of death.
'A qualified physician.
'there are some who believe my guise hid a darker identity.'
Bravo. River.
You chased the vermin to his death.
I say abort them.
Abort them all at birth.
But what release!
Better. surely. to die!
River!
RIVER!
Do not walk away from me. River!
Get off!
INDISTINCT VOICE ON RADIO
INDISTINCT YELLING AND CLAMOURING
Someone named you.
I bet it's that cow in HR.
Always does Adele.
I thought you couldn't eat chocolate.
I can't.
YELLING CONTINUES
They're humouring you.
In truth. they don't know what to do with you.
And they feel guilty.
They should have seen this coming.
You've never been entirely normal.
It's not like no-one notices.
Moustached Mike?
No-one drinks that much coffee.
Standing by the Nespresso machine.
cos they want to get a good view of the loon
talking to himself again.
It's humiliating.
I'm humiliated for you.
What?
You've always talked to yourself.
And who covered for you?
Kept you in check?
Screw you. Mr Magoo.
Who's Mr Magoo?
Little man. big nose.
The...Mr Magoo Show?
I think he had a dog.
The world thinks he's a lunatic
but he just needs glasses...
and won't admit it.
I don't have glasses. ENGINE STARTS
'Return from exercise. Return from exercise.
'Gentlemen. away from the fence. please. Away from the fence.'
INDISTINCT CHATTER
'If your segment is over. please return quickly to Block H.
'thank you.'
So. did you work with DS Stevenson long?
Yes.
Shouldn't we wait for his lawyer?
So. they've put you in with the big boys?
How's that going?
Aten?
Keep your head down and you'll be fine.
Where's my lawyer?
She's on her way.
OK. let's go again.
You walk her to the bus stop...
- We argued. I told you.
- Yeah.
And she says. "It's only a couple of hours on the train.
"We can still stay in touch."
We had a fight...
and she struggled.
You kill her?
You bury her. you burn her? I don't know.
You won't say how. you won't say where -
- but there's one thing you're adamant about.
- I killed her.
Yeah.
You have lichen under your nails.
rope fibres on your hands.
Did you tie her up?
You watched her die.
You have her skin under your nails...
..a spray of her blood on your T-shirt.
That bubble of blood and breath.
nobody tells you about that.
The agony of that -
watching someone you love dying.
I know you loved her.
I know what that love feels like.
(I can't do this no more. I can't.)
(I can't.)
I'm reading a book at the moment.
The Trial Of Dr Thomas Neill Cream.
There's a man who loved women.
He died in 1892.
He murdered nine. mostly by poisoning -
the last four. all prostitutes.
in the space of seven months.
Hanged here. in London. just a couple of miles away.
Coined "the Lambeth Poisoner".
He enjoyed...
- ..the agonies of his victims.
- Why are you telling me this?
I'm not that.
No. I don't think you are.
I've admitted I did it.
So. why don't I believe you?
You can admit it. but when I ask you where the body is...
I can't. I can't!
I know what it feels like.
doing nothing and watching someone you love die.
I know what it feels like...
'I'd like to conclude this interview now. please.'
When you hate the pulse of blood in your head...
- This is entirely unacceptable.
- ..because it reminds you
that you're alive and she's dead.
It's a kind of madness.
I will report this.
Yeah.
I'm sure you will.
Yeah. no. I'm fine.
These go right through me.
You get used to them.
Not that one.
He didn't do it.
Why would he confess if he didn't do it?
If he watched her die...
That doesn't mean he killed her.
What were you like as a teenager?
Short. Ugly. Spots.
Didn't get out of bed most days.
Listened to a lot of The Smiths.
You?
Were you depressed?
Aren't all teenagers at one time or another?
DOOR CLOSES
Course he's depressed.
He's murdered his girlfriend.
Well. even before that.
Teenagers write shit.
I didn't.
That's because you didn't have the internet.
If you had. you would have done.
- Would I?
- Yes.
You'd have written the same old shit as they all do.
"I love him. I hate him.
- "I hate myself..."
- RIVER LAUGHS
"I can't go on like this."
It's intense.
I wouldn't go back there if you paid me.
Like I said...
Yeah.
"Talk to her mother again."
I've got toothache.
Mosquitoes have 47 teeth.
How do they fit in such a tiny mouth?
I need to buy a television.
The KDL makes you feel closer to what you see.
It's full HD 3D with Dynamic Edge LED.
X-Reality PRO.
built-in Wi-Fi and internet...
- If you can just carry on. Thank you.
- Yes. sir.
Erm...
I'd like...
..to buy a television. please.
OK.
Let's start with the KDH LED.
POIGNANT MUSIC PLAYS
You know. you could have had that sent down
to be picked up as you left.
That's OK.
Did you get the tape?
I wasn't sure if you'd get it.
Why didn't Erin pack?
She was leaving the next day.
Young girls like to organise themselves. yet she didn't pack.
You still had to get the suitcase down.
We were getting around to it.
Ahh.
Only some of the comments in your e-mails...
72 days...
and still no body.
Now. if you can't do this for me. you've lied.
I wrote to the university. like you said.
I asked if they'd hold her place...
but they wouldn't.
She's got all A stars.
A star in English.
"She's dead. Mrs Fielding."
But she's not dead...
..cos I haven't got her body.
I've still got her train ticket.
I just want to feel the weight of her in my arms.
Even if it's bones and mud.
it's something.
Something of her.
She's mine.
I made her...
..and I will bury her.
I have to bury her.
so I know where she is.
You promised me you could give me that.
You both promised that.
How do you let go of a person...
..if you don't know why they've gone?
Everyone has a television.
You just plug it in.
That's all you need to do now.
They're already tuned.
You've got your...
..guide.
Oh.
Welcome to the 21st century.
You could download all this lot onto your phone.
Why would I do that?
More wall space.
For what?
River. I don't want you to take this the wrong way but...
- are you all right?
- Of course I am.
Revolver or Sgt Pepper?
Sgt Pepper.
Agreed.
- I'll see you in the morning then.
- Yeah.
You'll be all right?
Yeah.
DOOR CLOSES
Linda or Yoko?
Linda.
- Cos she's blonde?
- No.
- Cos she's blonde.
- No!
What you looking at?
You.
Where did you get this?
Your mother sent it.
What happened to you?
You're going to miss me.
You haven't gone yet.
You need to feed Stevie's cat.
CAT MEOWS
HE EXHALES
Hello. Bridie.
It was time to give the place a clean.
Are you bedding down here now?
No. no. no. I'm just here to...
- ..pick up the cat.
- Right.
I'd have taken it. only Frankie's allergic.
He's too soft...
..but you always spoil the youngest.
How are you. Bridie?
How do you think?
I thought we would have seen you before now.
I should have sent flowers.
What do I need flowers for?
So many flowers.
TAP RUNS
Did you get the invite...
for the wake?
Yeah.
I've said. "If they don't release her body by then.
"then I'm breaking in."
They agreed.
Fecking police.
You're all the same...
..and Stevie was no better.
She was made for a uniform.
Let's hope that little shit's your man.
You know.
we're all sad. John.
All broken.
I'm glad it was you.
I'm glad it was you by her side...
when she died.
CAT MEOWS
- All right. Frankie?
- All right?
You got the cat.
Your mother just...
Did she have a go at you?
Yeah. yeah. she had a pop.
I'll see you at the wake.
Do you think it was him?
Riley?
I hope so.
If it was...
Then we'll find out why.
If there's anything you need.
anything at all.
Did she...?
No. no.
No. she didn't suffer.
She died instantly.
Pretty instantly.
Frankie. a hand!
Will you please get your arse over here?
CAT MEOWS
Have no fear of robbers or murderers.
They are external dangers. petty danger.
We should fear ourselves.
the great dangers are within us.
What threatens our souls?
It is forbidden to kill.
therefore all murderers are punished...
unless they kill in large numbers
and to the sound of trumpets.
BUZZER
CAT MEOWS
Your tie's a bit...
DNA on Riley's car.
It's a match to DS Stevenson.
She hit the wing after she was shot.
Detective Sergeant Jackie Stevenson
was a brave and invaluable member of the police service.
and is still grieved for by her colleagues. friends and family.
This recent evidence suggests
that Mr Riley may be related
to this police officer's murder.
I will now hand over to my colleague.
Detective Chief Inspector Chrissie Read.
who will answer any further questions. Thank you.
THEY CLAMOUR
Please pace your questions. Thank you.
For DI River.
you must be feeling relieved today?
I'm saddened for the family.
Did you recognise him
as DS Stevenson's killer?
I mean. you witnessed her murder.
But I couldn't positively identify the murderer.
Yet you're certain that Mr Riley is a suspect?
DI River?
On... On seeing and approaching the car.
DI River identified it as the same...
- DISTORTED CLAMOURING
- Yes?
So. you are confident Mr Riley
IS Jackie Stevenson's killer?
No. we cannot confirm that.
but the vehicle he was driving
has been identified as the vehicle
driven by DS Stevenson's killer.
Well. I ask Detective Inspector River.
you are confident there will be justice. Inspector?
All murderers
are punished eventually...
..unless they kill in large numbers
and to the sound of trumpets.
For now. we have no further comments. Thank you.
Thank you very much indeed.
CLAMOURING
Psychs.
And you stay the whole session this time.
What the hell was that?
Now I have to go and face his poor girlfriend.
Yeah! Yeah. there he is! There's the murderer!
Do you read?
Soup labels.
washing instructions.
television manuals...
..and. on occasion. books.
Yes. I read.
I read a lot.
Shall we begin?
I have to tick my 12 boxes.
Have you experienced. or been exposed to. a traumatic event?
Yes.
During the traumatic event...
did you experience or witness serious injury or death.
or the threat of injury or death?
Yes.
During the traumatic event.
did you feel intense fear.
helplessness and/or horror?
- These questions are...
- They're...
They're just a framework
to get us started.
The second.
Helplessness?
OK. I'm going to skip a couple.
We'll come back to them.
Do you hallucinate.
have visions
or believe you see those who are now dead?
Yes.
Do you see ghosts?
Not ghosts. Not ghosts.
I don't believe in ghosts...
or heaven or hell.
It's not the afterlife kind.
Then what do you see?
Manifests.
You know. even though a person is dead.
the relationship with them does not end.
Well. people say that all the time. don't they?
But when you're dead. you're dead.
And it was Stevie. it wasn't like someone I was...
It wasn't someone you were...?
She was just a colleague.
Even if that was true.
there are still feelings.
Sadness.
Loss.
Guilt.
Even if you were just colleagues.
there was love. perhaps?
RIVER LAUGHS
Love...
I've been trying to remember what that feels like. to be in love.
It's been a while.
For whatever reason. it has passed me by.
The closest I got felt like food poisoning.
In books and films.
and plays. it's always so compelling. so complex.
There should be more than one word for love.
I've seen love that kills
and I've seen love that redeems.
I've seen love that...
believes in the guilty
and love that saves the bereaved.
What we will do for love.
Die for it. even.
DOOR OPENS
'Mum. it's me.
'I just wanted to say...
'I'll see you later.
'OK. I love you. Mum.'
'Mum. it's me.
'I just wanted to say...
'I'll see you later. OK.
'I love you. Mum.'
CROWS CAW
We were meant to do it together.
but he couldn't go through with it.
He tried to stop me.
it was just too late.
Why do you think he's so ashamed?
I never do go to university. do I?
No.
I climbed that tree and found her...
..and your rope too.
I'm sorry that you're not a murderer.
Just human.
You'll be released.
- ERIN:
- I still will stay with thee
and never. from this palace of dim night. depart again.
Here...
Here. will I remain.
with worms that are thy chambermaids.
Oh. here.
will I set up my everlasting rest...
RIVER JOINS IN: And shake the yoke of inauspicious stars
from this world-wearied flesh.
ONLY RIVER: Eyes. look your last.
Arms. take your last embrace.
And. lips...
Oh. you. the doors of breath.
..seal with a righteous kiss.
A dateless bargain
to engrossing death.
Come. bitter conduct.
Come. unsavoury guide!
Thou desperate pilot. now at once
run on the dashing rocks.
thy sea-sick weary bark!
Here's...
..to my love!
ATEN GASPS FOR AIR
You have to live.
It must be better to live than to die.
HE SOBS
That's right. Inspector.
"Heaven is here."
River...
River!
River. stop it!
There's no-one there.
I know.
Hi!
Oh. you've got a two-for-one voucher.
Yes. I know.
You're on your own?
- Yes. I'm on my own.
- OK. let me have a look.
Booth seven.
LIGHT TAPPING
Whitney...or Beyonce?
MUSIC: I Love To Love by Tina Charles
Sing. you nutter.
- Sing!
- # Wants to dance
# He loves to dance
# He's got to dance
# Oh. I love to love...
# But my baby just loves to dance
# Oh. I love to love
# But there's no time for our romance
# No. no. no
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# The minute the band begins to swing it
# He's on his feet to dig it
# And dance the night away
# Stop
# I'm spinning like a top
# We'll dance until we drop
# But if I had my way
# Oh. I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# Stop
# I'm spinning like a top
# We'll dance until we drop... #
I didn't do it.
Want me to sing you to sleep?
# Stop
# I'm spinning like a top
# We'll dance until we drop
# But if I had my way
# Sundown
# Instead of going downtown
# We'll stay at home and get down
# To what I'm trying to say
# I love to love
# But my baby just loves to dance
# Yeah. yeah
# Whoo! #